<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer on Dany Nativel</title>
    <link>https://danynativel.net/categories/computer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer on Dany Nativel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danynativel.net/categories/computer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchLinux Installation Guide on Encrypted SSD [2017]</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2017/01/29/archlinux-installation-guide-on-encrypted-ssd-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2017/01/29/archlinux-installation-guide-on-encrypted-ssd-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will guide you for installing ArchLinux on a GPT partition while using GRUB2 on a BIOS enabled PC (see Wiki for EFI) and thus on a SSD media based upon LUKS (encryption) over LVM. It is not aimed to replace the official ArchLinux installation guide or Wiki. It is just a collection of notes gathered from the official sources. As a reminder the Installation Guide can now also be found on the USB flash drive under /root/install.txt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArchLinux Installation Guide on Encrypted SSD</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2015/12/20/archlinux-installation-guide-on-encrypted-ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2015/12/20/archlinux-installation-guide-on-encrypted-ssd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;WARNING!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://danynativel.net/2017/01/29/archlinux-installation-guide-on-encrypted-ssd-2017/&#39;&gt;2017 version of this installation guide can be found here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will guide you for installing ArchLinux on a GPT partition while using GRUB2 on a BIOS enabled PC (see Wiki for EFI) and thus on a SSD media based upon LUKS (encryption) over LVM. It is not aimed to replace the official ArchLinux installation guide or Wiki. It is just a collection of notes gathered from the official sources. As a reminder the Installation Guide can now also be found on the USB flash drive under /root/install.txt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Rsync daemon on unRAID</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2013/10/21/enabling-rsync-daemon-on-unraid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2013/10/21/enabling-rsync-daemon-on-unraid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to rsync my data using a CIFS mount of the corresponding /mnt/user/share found on unRAID. I noticed that some of the files kept uploading even if they haven&amp;rsquo;t been modified. I also had issues with some long directories containing files with long filenames. After enabling rsync daemon on unRAID, all my problems went away and transfert speed was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting git-annex to run on unRAID</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2013/10/21/getting-git-annex-to-run-on-unraid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2013/10/21/getting-git-annex-to-run-on-unraid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://git-annex.branchable.com/&#34;&gt;git-annex&lt;/a&gt; is an appealing Open Source replacement for Dropbox. You can easily install it on unRAID by following some easy steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to unRAID 5.0 Release</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2013/09/26/migrating-to-unraid-5-0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2013/09/26/migrating-to-unraid-5-0-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;unRAID 5.0 has now  been officially released. Considering the significant changes, upgrade is not as smooth as it used to be so it is better to start off from scratch with a clean USB drive that only contains disk configuration. With the new add-ons management options it requires less tweaking in the &amp;lsquo;go&amp;rsquo; startup file. Please read the release note. Depending of your current version you might just have to upgrade the unRaid image while with other (i.e. any 5.0 beta) it is advised to go through a fresh installation while using exisiting disk configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergency commands for encrypted Archlinux installations</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2013/06/10/emergency-commands-for-encrypted-archlinux-installations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2013/06/10/emergency-commands-for-encrypted-archlinux-installations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ArchLinux is a fantastic rolling distribution but sometimes you will end up with a broken or semi-broken system that you need to fix. Getting back on tracks might sound even scarier when running a full disk encryption installation on SSD but LVM brings some nice goodies that will make your life easier. For information, I have run LUKS encryption on LVM for many years and I can tell you that it is rock solid and very robust. I have tortured it many many times, powered it off without any notice and haven&amp;rsquo;t (yet) lost a single bit of data, although there is always this half second pause after entering the initial passphrase that makes you think &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;is it going to be able to decrypt my drive?&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnome 3.8 tweaks</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2013/05/05/gnome-3-8-tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2013/05/05/gnome-3-8-tweaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gnome 3.8 brings a number of nice new changes such as support for Owncloud storage, a redesigned application launching view, enhanced search, new privacy settings, a new classic mode, improved animation rendering, a new Clocks application, heavily updated settings and many of updates to GNOME applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the many other improvements GNOME 3.8 in &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/3.8/&#34;&gt;release notes.&lt;/a&gt;
Gnome 3.8 broke few things on my system. Here is my experience so far under ArchLinux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting-up a HTPC with XBMC and ArchLinux</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2013/03/10/setting-up-a-htpc-with-xbmc-and-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2013/03/10/setting-up-a-htpc-with-xbmc-and-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will guide you through an installation of XBMC on top of ArchLinux and thus using a GPT partition and GRUB2 on a BIOS enabled PC (see Wiki for EFI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clone MiFare cards using Chinesse UUID writable cards</title>
      <link>https://danynativel.net/2012/08/09/clone-mifare-cards-using-chinesse-uuid-writable-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danynativel.net/2012/08/09/clone-mifare-cards-using-chinesse-uuid-writable-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;libnfc supports UUID writable cards and even has some dedicated tools for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with some of the cards found on eBay that are even simpler to use. Sector 0 is unlocked and can be written without any additional commands. libnfc requires a small patch to get it working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following has been tested under ArchLinux with modified libnfc 1.5.1, mfoc 0.10.2 and a SCL3711 dongle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>